fertilethoughts.com 2012-04-06

# FertileThoughts.com - The World's Largest Fertility Community

This Privacy Policy was last modified and is effective as of Monday July 5, 2010. 

## FertileThoughts.com Privacy Policy

Please read our Privacy Policy carefully to be sure you understand how we collect and use information and under what circumstances we share information about you. 

## We Can Modify this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify, add or delete provisions of this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time, and we will post a notice and the effective date of any change on our Website. Your use of our Website after the effective date of any such modification means you accept and agree to be bound by the Privacy Policy, as modified. We urge you to come back to this web page and review this Privacy Policy regularly so that you remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply to you. 

## Collecting Personal Information

"Personal Information" means any information obtained through your use of our Website which might reasonably be used to specifically identify you and may include your name, address, email and phone number, among other things. If and when we collect Personal Information from you, we do so on a voluntary basis and this enables us to give you access to the registered users portions of our Website which may include features, functions, promotions, products and services not generally available to non-registered users. 

We do not sell or rent your Personal Information to others. If necessary, our Website may collect payment and payment instrument information from you for the purpose of billing you for products and services you purchase through our Website. Bear in mind, if you leave our Website whether by clicking or selecting an advertisement, re-directing your browser or otherwise, their terms and conditions, privacy and other policies and practices will apply, not ours. 

## Collecting Non-Personal Information

When you use our Website, we often use third party operational service providers and technology that can recognize, collect and transmit information that is associated with you or your computer and browser, but which does not personally identify you. Although the term "cookie" commonly is used to refer to a small text file stored on a computer that keeps track of your visits to web sites and/or can contain log-in information so you don't have to re-enter information each time you visit, we will use the term "cookie" to refer generically to any technology that can recognize, collect or transmit information about your visits to our Website. "Cookie" information typically includes such data as the Internet or web domain that referred you, the type of operating system and browser you are using, the date and time of your visit, information relating to activities on our Websites (e.g., 'clickstream' data) and other technical attributes of your visits to our Website. No personally identifiable information is collected by this process and we use the information collected through cookies to analyze trends, administer our Website, track movements on our Website and gather aggregate demographic information about visitors so we can continually improve our Website. 

Cookies store information that allows our Website to recognize a users' computer or access device each time it is used to visit our Website and cookies can keep count of how often you return to our Website. Cookies can also track how you use our Website, your preferences for features and functions and can store information such as your log-in information, so you don't have to re-enter them each time you return to our Website. We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer for purposes that are unrelated to our Website or your interaction with our Website. 

You may stop or restrict cookies on your computer or purge them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences and you should consult the operating instructions that apply to your browser for instructions should you wish to do so and in general to determine how best to configure your browser settings to meet your requirements. Note that if you 'turn off,' purge or disable cookies, although you may still use our Website, you may not be able to use all of the features, functions or services available on our Website. 

## How We Use Your Information

We will only use information we collect or obtain when you use our Website as described in this Privacy Policy, for our internal research purposes. If, at any time in the future, we decide we are going to use your Personal Information in a way that differs from our then current Privacy Policy, we will give you notice as described in the section above entitled "We Can Modify This Privacy Policy," at least 30 days' in advance notice. We will provide you the opportunity to decline consent ("opt-out") of such differing uses. 

## ADVERTISERS, CO-SPONSORS AND LINKS TO OTHERS

Our Website may contain or display information from sponsors, co-sponsors, advertisers, operational service providers or others that offer to make information, products and services available, provide opportunities to participate in promotions or engage in activities or that link or redirect your browser to other websites, web pages, materials or organizations. We may also use third parties for the purpose of administering, operating, configuring our Website, maintaining and providing internal support for our Website and Content on our Website, to display and serve advertising on our Website, for distributing our online, email, messaged or web-based newsletters and other information. We will refer to these third parties as our "operational service providers." Even if we have a relationship with a third party you may encounter or see on our Website, the advertising, links or references to third parties or any of their websites, including any cookies or other technology they may use, are not under our control and they have their own terms, conditions, policies and practices that apply to you in connection with their websites, including those concerning collection, use and disclosure of your information (including Personal Information). 

Some FertileThoughts.com Services, such as seminars, educational events, conferences, newsletters, blogs, and discussion groups, may be co-sponsored in conjunction with other companies that not under the control of FertileThoughts.com. Whenever we are involved in the provision of these Services, we will disclose the name of our co-sponsor and to the extent they are Website-based, we will advise you if any of the privacy practices, policies or terms that apply to those particular Services are different from those set forth in this Privacy Policy. Co-sponsors of these IAB Services are not under our control and when you participate, register or engage in other online activities related to these co-sponsored IAB Services, you should be aware that you are providing your information, which may include Personal Information, to us and the co-sponsor and that their policies, practices, terms and conditions, and not ours, apply to their collection and use of your information. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Website or take advantage of advertised offers, links or other references, many of which may direct you or your Internet browser to websites or web pages of another party. You should read their privacy statements and the terms and conditions that apply, because we are not responsible for any of the terms or conditions, privacy practices, the content, functions, features, activities or transactions you may engage in when you are not using our Website. 

## Disclosure to Third Parties

We always have the right to disclose your Personal Information to our operational service providers that we engage to assist us in connection with our Website or other services we provide. We always request that our operational service providers protect your privacy and not disclose your Personal Information to third party marketers that are not associated with our Website, nor are they permitted to use your Personal Information for their own marketing or promotional purposes. 

If we use an operational service provider to serve advertising when you visit our Website, they, in connection with our Website, may use information about your visit to our Website in order to serve advertisements about products and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements to our Website, our operational service provider may use cookies. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by the operational service provider we use for this service, please click here: advertising service provider link. 

We also currently use an operational service provider to measure our Website traffic and they may also information (but not Personal Information) about your use of our Website to help us improve our Website. If you would like more information about how the operational service provider we use for this service collects and uses this information, please visit: traffic service provider link. 

We also reserve the right to make your Personal Information available: 

  * When compelled by a governmental agency, law, regulation, a court or other legal process; 

  * If we believe you are or may be a threat to safety, security, property, interests or rights of us or anyone else; 

  * In order to investigate, respond to or resolve problems or inquiries or protect, enforce or defend our rights, assets and/or interests; 

  * In a merger, acquisition, change of control, joint venture or other business combination. 

## Opting Out

If you register on or with our Website, you are agreeing and consenting to receive information and updates about your use of our Website or our Services for which you register. You may opt out of receiving any or all of these communications by sending an email to [unsubscribe@fertilityauthority.com](mailto:unsubscribe@fertilityauthority.com), by following the unsubscribe procedures on our Website or by following the unsubscribe instructions we will include in each email we send you. 

## Security

As you may appreciate, the Internet is a public network of networks and we cannot guarantee that communications between you and FertileThoughts.com or others to, through or from our Website, will be free from unauthorized access or interference by third parties such as hackers. By using our Website, you are agreeing to assume this risk and any and all responsibility and liability that may arise. That said, the security of your Personal Information is important to us and when possible we attempt to provide secure transmissions by using encryption software. We have also put in place reasonable physical, electronic and operational procedures to safeguard information and we limit access to your Personal Information to only those employees who need access in order to perform their duties. 

## Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Information

We will provide you with a mechanism to allow and enable you to correct or update the Personal Information in our current records that we have obtained from you. You can always review and change your Personal Information by contacting us by email at [info@fertilityauthority.com](mailto:info@fertilityauthority.com). Certain Personal Information may not be changed without authentication (e.g., birth date) and you may be asked to provide additional information to allow us to confirm your identity in order to change those. If you ask us to remove your Personal Information, we still reserve the right to retain as much of your Personal Information and for so long as necessary to comply with our legal, regulatory, internal audit and record-keeping requirements. 

## Contact Us

For questions or concerns relating to privacy, we can be contacted at: [info@fertilityauthority.com](mailto:info@fertilityauthority.com).
